

Evgenii Kotelnikov, Ph.D.

Date of birth: 15 February 1990

Current location: Gothenburg, Sweden (open to relocation)

I am a software developer and a computer scientist dedicated to improving the quality of software

My academic background is a Ph.D. in Computer Science on the topic of automated theorem proving.

through the use of static analysis, formal verification, functional programming and advanced type systems.

Over the last 15 years I worked as a software developer within Cloud, Web, Telecom and Automotive.

I have worked in several different tech stacks, and my preferred day-to-day ones are C, Python, Scala and Haskell.

Work experience

in My LinkedIn profile

February 2021 to now 🛗

Gothenburg, Sweden 9

Zenseact AB

Software developer

Zenseact develops an autonomous driving platform for Volvo Cars.

- Develop safety critical software components of self-driving cars in C, C++ and Ada.
- Scout for requirements, breakdown, refine and formalize.
- Integrate the SPARK verification toolchain into the company's codebase.
- Formally verify safety requirements of the core components in SPARK. **SPARK** C++ Python Ada

Ericsson AB

August 2019 to January 2021 ## Gothenburg, Sweden 9

• Implemented new features for the control plane of SGSN-MME in Erlang.

Software developer

• Helped to migrate Ericsson's 5G platform from custom hardware to the telco cloud. Among other things, implemented a

cloud-based storage and logging infrastructure for it. Linux Erlang С Bash Python Kubernetes Docker

Chalmers University of Technology

September 2013 to September 2018 🛗 Gothenburg, Sweden 9

Doctoral researcher

• Conducted research in the areas of automated theorem proving, formal methods and functional programming.

- Published and presented academic results in conferences and workshops (see my Google Scholar profile).
- Actively contributed to Vampire, a state-of-the-art automated theorem prover for first-order logic.
- Assisted to preparing assignments, conducting consultation sessions and grading exams in the courses on Functional
- Programming, Databases, Algorithms and Datastructures. Developed and maintained a homework submission system in the Computer Science department used annually by
- approx. 1000 students and 20 faculty members. Java Haskell Python PostgreSQL Oracle Database

Amazon Web Services

Applied scientist intern, Automated Reasoning Group

March 2017 to June 2017 ## New York, USA ?

Implemented an experimental backend for Tiros — a static analyzer of AWS virtual private cloud networks.

Scala Python Datalog Vampire **Z**3

Yandex Inc.

March 2011 to August 2013 ## Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

Software developer Developed the back end of high-load web search services, including an in-house performant database solution

Software engineering intern

MySQL

capable of serving up to 400 requests per second. Developed information retrieval tools and web crawlers.

Redis

Developed an app recommendation system for Yandex. Store.

Akka Oracle Database MongoDB Java Scala

> July 2010 to December 2010 ## Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

> > 2005 to 2010 mm

Motorola Solutions Inc.

Designed a specification language for low-level telecom protocols and implemented a toolchain for it. Python Wireshark Lisp C

JavaScript

Web developer Remote 9 Developed front end and back end of commercial websites.

jQuery

CSS

HTML

Doctor of philosophy (Ph.D.)

Scala

vampire C++

Education

Freelance

PHP

Thesis titled "Automated Theorem Proving with Extensions of First-Order Logic"

September 2013 to September 2018 ##

Gothenburg, Sweden 9

Ph.D. supervisors Laura Kovács and Andrei Voronkov

Chalmers University of Technology, Department of Computer Science

in. The applications include automation of proof assistants and static analysis of software and networks. Static analysis Automated theorem proving Formal methods First-order logic Vampire

Explored ways to make automated theorem provers more efficient for applications by extending the logic that they reason

Master of science (M.Sc.) September 2011 to July 2013 ##

Saint-Petersburg State University, Department of Applied Mathematics Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9 Thesis titled "Syntactical Extensions of Scala for Effectful Computations"

Monads

Bachelor of science (B.Sc.) September 2007 to July 2011 🛗 Saint-Petersburg State University, Department of Applied Mathematics Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

Computational effects

Thesis titled "Source Code Generation Based on Language Grammar Description" Source code generation Context-free grammars

Metaprogramming

Scheme

Public software projects

My GitHub profile

An award-winning automated theorem prover A verification conditions generator for the Boogie for first-order logic. intermediate verification language.

scala-workflow Scala atomizer Erlang An extension to Scala for boilerplate-free syntax for effectful A static analysis tool for finding loose atoms

fire atp Python CoffeeScript Haskell HTML Docker

Haskell interface to automated theorem provers.

computations.

in large Erlang code bases.

A submission system for homework assignments.

Haskell

Algebraic data types

voogie